<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Kobe and Pascal</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/</link><description>Recent content on Kobe and Pascal</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>; &lt;a href=</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 05:23:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://kobeandpascal.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Julius Caesar by William Shakespeare</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/shakespeare/julius_caesar/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 05:23:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/shakespeare/julius_caesar/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A few beautiful lines from &lt;em&gt;Julius Caesar&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cassius; lean and hungry&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CASSIUS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I know that virtue to be in your, Brutus,&lt;br&gt;
As well as I do know your outward favor.&lt;br&gt;
Well, honor is the subject of my story.&lt;br&gt;
I cannot tell what you and other men&lt;br&gt;
Think of this life; but for my single self,&lt;br&gt;
I had as lief not be, as live to be&lt;br&gt;
In awe of such a thing as I myself.&lt;br&gt;
I was born free as Caesar, so were you.&lt;br&gt;
We both have fed as well, and we can both&lt;br&gt;
Endure the winter&amp;rsquo;s cold as well as he.&lt;br&gt;
For once upon a raw and gusty day,&lt;br&gt;
The troubled Tiber chafing with her shoes,&lt;br&gt;
Said Caesar to me &amp;ldquo;Dar&amp;rsquo;st thou, Cassius, now&lt;br&gt;
Leap in with me into this angry flood,&lt;br&gt;
And swim to yonder point?&amp;rdquo; Upon the word,&lt;br&gt;
Accoutred as I was I plunged in,&lt;br&gt;
And bade him follow. So indeed he did.&lt;br&gt;
The torrent roared, and we did buffet it&lt;br&gt;
With lusty sinews, throwing it aside,&lt;br&gt;
And stemming it with hearts of controversy.&lt;br&gt;
But ere we could arrive the point proposed,&lt;br&gt;
Caesar cried &amp;ldquo;Help me, Cassius, or I sink!&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
Ay, as Aeneas our great ancestor&lt;br&gt;
Did from the flames of Troy upon his shoulder.&lt;br&gt;
The old Anchises bear, so from the waves of Tiber&lt;br&gt;
Did I the tired Caesar. And this man&lt;br&gt;
Is now become a god, and Cassius is&lt;br&gt;
A wretched creature, and must bend his body&lt;br&gt;
If Caesar carelessly but nod on him.&lt;br&gt;
He has a fever when he was in Spain,&lt;br&gt;
And when the fit was on him, I did mark&lt;br&gt;
How he did shake. &amp;lsquo;Tis true, this god did shake.&lt;br&gt;
His coward lips did from their color fly;&lt;br&gt;
And that same eye whose bend doth awe the world&lt;br&gt;
Did lose his luster. I did hear him groan,&lt;br&gt;
Ay, and that tongue of his that bade the Romans&lt;br&gt;
Mark him and write his speeches in their books,&lt;br&gt;
&amp;ldquo;Alas!&amp;rdquo; it cried, &amp;ldquo;Give me some drink, Titinius,&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
As a sick girl. Ye gods, it doth amaze me&lt;br&gt;
A man of such a feeble temper should&lt;br&gt;
So get the start of the majestic world,&lt;br&gt;
And bear the palm alone!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Flourish and shout within&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Notes from 'Breeding Superman: Nietzsche, Race and Eugenics in Edwardian and Interwar Britain'</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/nietzsche/breeding_superman_stone/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 23:08:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/nietzsche/breeding_superman_stone/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Breeding Superman: Nietzsche, Race and Eugenics in Edwardian and Interwar Britian, by Dan Stone&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My contention is that in Britain the ideas existed without the movement, even
before the rise of fascism in Italy and Nazism in Germany. Historians are
correct to note that fascism was squeezed out of the political process in the
interwar period. But I also argue that this outcome was by no means as
inevitable as the Whiggish historiography suggests, especially in the context
of the radical right before 1914. The manifold, radical ideas that feed fascism&amp;mdash; whether or not they subsequently guide it in power is not here the question&amp;mdash;existed in abundance in Britain, especially in the Edwardian cultural sphere,
as I demonstrate below. British fascism failed not because it was an imitative
movement, but because mainstream conservatism did not need to co-opt its ideas
in order to remain in power.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Notes on Christopher Hill's 'The World Turned Upside Down'</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/christopher_hill/world_upside_down_notes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:36:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/christopher_hill/world_upside_down_notes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Some quotes, notes and scribblings on a now famous book on the age of infant
Capitalism in England &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;The World Turned Upside Down&amp;rdquo; by Christopher Hill. It
is remarkable how contemporary these seedlings of revolution feel, the
ethics, shared understandings of power, and the materialism of so much of the so
called sacred world of authority. These folks were far from misunderstanding
brutes, mean multitudes. They were people fighting for a better life, and they
knew in their bones they deserved it.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Notes on Minqi Li's 'The Rise of China and the Demise of the Capitalist World Economy</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/minqi_li/notes_rise_of_china/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 01:52:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/minqi_li/notes_rise_of_china/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Notes on a terrific work in political economy. Extremely pertinent to our
present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Suppose, in response to the current crisis of neoliberalism, global capitalism
is restructured with a greater degree of state intervention and more equal
distribution of income (is this not what much of the world&amp;rsquo;s intellectual Left
is hoping for at the moment?), would it not be expected that in at most two or
three decades, there would be a new global profitability crisis? What should the
world&amp;rsquo;s working classes (and the intellectual Left) do then? Wait for another
round of 30 years of neoliberalism to play itself out?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unique by Castoriadis</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/castoriadis_quote/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 04:06:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/castoriadis_quote/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It is possible that at times people drape themselves in Roman tunics to play
the bourgeois revolution&amp;mdash;or that a general wnats to play Joan of Arc in
twentieth-century dress; but how is it that, in real history, it is never
Zerlina who replies to Agamemnon and that Brutus never has Monsieur Perrichon
for his friend and confidant?&lt;/em&gt; - Cornelius Castoriadis&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>And Quite Flows the Don</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/quite-flows-the-don/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 10:33:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/quite-flows-the-don/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By Mikhail Sholokhov,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How human beings have sullied, have poisoned the world! How much human misery
has been poured out! She turned passionately towards Bunchuk and sought for his
hand. &amp;lsquo;Tell me, wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be sweet to die for that? Tell me! Yes? What is
there to believe in, if not in that? What is one to live for? It seems to me
that if I die in the struggle&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo; She pressed his hand to her chest so that he
felt the muffled beating of her heart, and gazing up at him with a deep,
darkened glance, she whispered: &amp;lsquo;&amp;hellip; and if death is not instantaneous, then
the last thing I shall feel will be that triumphant, disturbingly beautiful
music of the future.&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Past by Gorky</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/gorky/the-past-quote/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 03:40:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/gorky/the-past-quote/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is not meant as a reproach. The past is not irreproachable, but there is no sense in reproaching it. It should be studied.&lt;/em&gt; &amp;ndash; Maxim Gorky&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Some Reflections on 'The Gift' by Marcel Mauss</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/reflections-on-thegift-mauss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 02:40:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/reflections-on-thegift-mauss/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A few excerpts from the tremendous text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;These peoples [Melanesian tribes] possess an extra domestic economy and a very
developed system of exchange that throbs with life more intensely and more
precipitantly perhaps than the one that our peasants or the fishing villages
along our coasts were familiar with maybe not even a hundred years ago. They
have an extensive economic life, going beyond the confines of the islands and
their dialects, which represents a considerable trade. Through gifts made and
reciprocated they have robustly replaced a system of buying and selling.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Computational Biology for Autodidacts</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/computational-biology-for-autodidacts/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/computational-biology-for-autodidacts/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Education is our passport to the future, for tomorrow belongs to those who prepare for it today&amp;rdquo;
&amp;ndash; Malcolm X&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time I was labouring about with pipettes in hand, cutting and
pasting plasmids, asking questions about the edibility of my agarose gels. I
eventually parted ways with the wet lab and moved into teaching myself
Computational skills that I could apply to Biological questions. The journey
has been one of the most exciting, challenging but ultimately fulfilling. There
is a persistence that the auto-didactic approach requires; a humility and
continually curious energy. Given that Biology proper is increasingly pulling
from the Computational spheres in order to effectively pursue certain
questions, it is becoming increasingly important to be literate in these
spheres. Even a basic understanding of key concepts will take one quite far.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Braudel, a Dialectician?</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/braudel-a-dialectician/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2022 07:38:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/braudel-a-dialectician/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Eternal Now by Paul Tillich</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/eternalnow/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Sep 2022 01:07:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/eternalnow/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;What follows are some of my favorite excerpts from the Theologian Paul Tillich&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;lsquo;The Eternal Now&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They withdraw into a self-chosen loneliness, taking revenge through bitterness
and hostility towards those they feel have rejected them, actually enjoying the
pain of their loneliness.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;One of these ways is the desire towards the silence of nature. We can speak
without voice to the trees and the clouds and the waves of the sea. Without
words they respond though the rustling of leaves and the moving of clouds and
the murmuring of the sea.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Was Too Small by Bertolt Brecht</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/was-too-small-brecht/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 09:19:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/was-too-small-brecht/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Yes, it is me. Shui Ta and Shen Teh, I am both of them.&lt;br&gt;
Your original order&lt;br&gt;
To be good while yet surviving&lt;br&gt;
Split me like lightning into two people. I&lt;br&gt;
Cannot tell what occurred: goodness to others&lt;br&gt;
And to myself could not both be achieved.&lt;br&gt;
To serve both self and others I found too hard.&lt;br&gt;
Oh, your world is arduous! Such need, such description!&lt;br&gt;
The hand which is held out to the starving&lt;br&gt;
Is quickly wrenched off! He who gives help to the lost&lt;br&gt;
Is lost for his own part! For who could&lt;br&gt;
Hold himself back from anger when the hungry are dying?&lt;br&gt;
Where could I find so much that was needed, if not&lt;br&gt;
In myself? But that was my downfall! The load of comandements&lt;br&gt;
Forced me into the sludge. Yet if I broke the rules&lt;br&gt;
I strode proudly around, and could eat myself full!&lt;br&gt;
Something is wrong with this world of yours. Why&lt;br&gt;
Is wickedness so rewarded, and why is so much suffering&lt;br&gt;
Reserved for the good? Of, I felt such&lt;br&gt;
Temptation to treat myself kindly! I felt too&lt;br&gt;
A secret awareness inside me, for my foster-mother&lt;br&gt;
Washed me with slops from the gutter! So I acquired&lt;br&gt;
A sharp eye. A yet pity&lt;br&gt;
Brought me such pain that I at once felt wolfish anger&lt;br&gt;
At the sight of misery. Then&lt;br&gt;
I could feel how I gradually altered and&lt;br&gt;
My lips grew tight and hard. Bitter as ashes&lt;br&gt;
The kind word felt in my mouth. And yet&lt;br&gt;
I should gladly have been an Angel to the slums. For giving&lt;br&gt;
Was still my delight. A smiling face&lt;br&gt;
And I walked in the clouds.&lt;br&gt;
Condemn me: each of my crimes&lt;br&gt;
Was committed to help out my neighbour&lt;br&gt;
To love my beloved or&lt;br&gt;
To save my young song from going without.&lt;br&gt;
O gods, for your vast projects&lt;br&gt;
I, poor human, was too small.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Good and the Gods by Bertolt Brecht</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/the-good-and-the-gods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 04:29:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/the-good-and-the-gods/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From the Interlude of &amp;ldquo;The Good Person of Szechwan&amp;rdquo; by Bertolt Brecht - John Willet Translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song of the Defencelessness of the Good and the Gods&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
In our country&lt;br&gt;
The capable man needs luck. Only&lt;br&gt;
If he has mighty backers&lt;br&gt;
Can he prove his capacity.&lt;br&gt;
The good&lt;br&gt;
Have no means of helping themselves and the gods are&lt;br&gt;
powerless.&lt;br&gt;
So why can&amp;rsquo;t the gods launch a great operation&lt;br&gt;
With bombers and battleships, tanks and destroyers&lt;br&gt;
And rescue the good by a ruthless invasion?&lt;br&gt;
Then mabe the wicked would cease to annoy use.&lt;br&gt;
\&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;She puts on Shui Ta&amp;rsquo;s costume and takes a few steps in his way of walking&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
\&lt;br&gt;
The good&lt;br&gt;
Cannot remain good for long in our country&lt;br&gt;
Where cupboards are bare, housewives start to squabble.&lt;br&gt;
Oh, the divine commandments&lt;br&gt;
Are not much use against hunger.&lt;br&gt;
So why can&amp;rsquo;t the gods share out what they&amp;rsquo;ve created&lt;br&gt;
Come down and distribute the bounties of nature&lt;br&gt;
And allow us, once hunger and thirst have been sated&lt;br&gt;
To mix with each other in friendship and pleasure?&lt;br&gt;
\&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;She dons Shui Ta&amp;rsquo;s mask and sings on in his voice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
\&lt;br&gt;
In order to win one&amp;rsquo;s mid-day meal&lt;br&gt;
One needs the toughness which elsewhere builds empires.&lt;br&gt;
Except twelve others be trampled down&lt;br&gt;
The unfortunate cannot be helped.&lt;br&gt;
So why can&amp;rsquo;t the gods make a simple decision&lt;br&gt;
That goodness must conquer in spite of its weakness? &amp;ndash;&lt;br&gt;
Then back up the good with an armoured division&lt;br&gt;
Command it to: &amp;lsquo;fire!&amp;rsquo; and not tolerate meekness?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>City at Dawn by Bertolt Brecht</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/city-at-dawn/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 04:19:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/city-at-dawn/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From Scene Four of &amp;ldquo;The Good Person of Szechwan&amp;rdquo; by Bertolt Brecht - John Willet Translation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;to the audience&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; I had never seen the city at dawn. These
were the hours when I used to lie with my filthy blanket over my head,
terrified to wake up. Today I mixed with the newsboys, with the men who were
washing down the streets, with the ox-carts bringing fresh vegetables in from
the fields. It was a long walk from Sun&amp;rsquo;s neighbourhood to here, but with ever
step I grew happier. I had always been told that when one is in love one walks
on air, but the wonderful thing is that one walks on earth, on tarmac. I tell
you, at dawn the blocks of buildings are like rubbish heaps with little lights
glowing in them; the sky is pink but still transparent, clear of dust. I tell
you, you miss a great deal if you are not in love and cannot see your city at
that hour when she rises from her couch like a sober old crafstman, filling his
lungs with fresh air and reaching for his tools, as the poets have it. &lt;em&gt;To the
group waiting&lt;/em&gt;: Good morning! Here is your rice! &lt;em&gt;She shares it out, then
notices Wang&lt;/em&gt;: Good morning, Wang. I am light-headed today. All the way I
looked at my reflection in the shop windows, and now I would like to buy myself
a shawl. &lt;em&gt;After a short hesitation&lt;/em&gt;: I should so like to look beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Airmen Not Wanted by Bertolt Brecht</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/sun-the-airman-with-no-mail/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 03:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/sun-the-airman-with-no-mail/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From Scene Three of &amp;ldquo;The Good Person of Szechwan&amp;rdquo; by Bertolt Brecht - John Willet Translation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It starts raining.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; What&amp;rsquo;s that rope for? You&amp;rsquo;re not to do it!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; Mind you&amp;rsquo;re own business! And get out of the way!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s raining.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; Don&amp;rsquo;t you try sheltering under my tree.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;remains motionless in the rain&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; No.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; Why not give up, sister, it&amp;rsquo;s no use. You can&amp;rsquo;t do business with me. Besides, you&amp;rsquo;re too ugly, Bandy legs.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; That&amp;rsquo;s not true.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t want to see them! All right, come under the bloody tree, since it&amp;rsquo;s raining!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;She approaches slowly and sites down under the tree.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; Why do you want to do that?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; Would you like to know? Then I&amp;rsquo;ll tell you, so as to be rid of you. &lt;em&gt;Pause.&lt;/em&gt; Do you know what an airman is?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, I once saw some airmen in a teahouse.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; Oh no you didn&amp;rsquo;t. One or two windy idiots in flying helmets, I expect: the sort who&amp;rsquo;s got no ear for his enginge and no feeling for his machine. Gets into a kite by bribing the hangar superintendent. Tell a type life that: now stall your crate at 2,000, down through the clouds, then catch her up with the flick of a stick, and he&amp;rsquo;ll say: But that&amp;rsquo;s not in the book. If you can&amp;rsquo;t land your kite gently as lowering your bottom you&amp;rsquo;re not an airman, you&amp;rsquo;re an idiot. Me, I&amp;rsquo;m an airman. And yet I&amp;rsquo;m the biggest idiot of the lot, because I read all the manuals in flying school as Pekin. But just one page of one manual I happened to miss, the one where it says Airmen Not Wanted. And so I became an airman without an aircraft, a mail pilot without mail. What that means you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t understand.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; I think I do understand all the same.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; No, I&amp;rsquo;m telling you you can&amp;rsquo;t understand. And that means you can&amp;rsquo;t understand.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;half laughing, half crying&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; When we were children we had a crane with a broken wing. He was very tame and didn&amp;rsquo;t mind our teasing him, and used to come strutting after us and scream if we went too fast for him. But in the autumn and the spring, when the great flocks of birds flew over our village, hebecame very restless, and I could understand why.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; Stop crying.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; Yes.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s bad for the complexion.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m stopping.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;She dries her tears on her sleeve. Leaning against the tree, but without turning towards her, he reaches for her face.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; You don&amp;rsquo;t even know how to wipe your face properly.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;He wipes it for her with a handkerchief&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; If you&amp;rsquo;ve got to sit there and stop me for hanging myself you might at least say something.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t know what.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Sun:&lt;/strong&gt; Why do you want to hack me down, sister, as a matter of interest?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Shen Teh:&lt;/strong&gt; It frightens me. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you only felt like that because the evening&amp;rsquo;s so dreary. &lt;em&gt;To the audience&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;br&gt;
In our country&lt;br&gt;
There should be no dreary evenings&lt;br&gt;
Or tall bridges over rivers&lt;br&gt;
Even the hour between night and morning&lt;br&gt;
And the whole winter season too, is dangerous.&lt;br&gt;
For in the face of misery&lt;br&gt;
Only a little is needed&lt;br&gt;
Before men start throwing&lt;br&gt;
Their unbearable life away.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Song of the Smoke by Bertolt Brecht</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/song-of-the-smoke-brecht/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2022 02:51:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/song-of-the-smoke-brecht/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From Scene One of &amp;ldquo;The Good Person of Szechwan&amp;rdquo; - John Willet translation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Grandfather:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Once I believed intelligence would aid me
I was an optimist when I was younger&lt;br&gt;
Now that I&amp;rsquo;m old I see it hasn&amp;rsquo;t paid me:
How can intelligence compete with hunger?&lt;br&gt;
And so I said: drop it!&lt;br&gt;
Like smoke twisting grey&lt;br&gt;
Into ever colder coldness you&amp;rsquo;ll
Blow away.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The man:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I saw the conscientious man get nowhere&lt;br&gt;
And so I tired the crooked path instead&lt;br&gt;
But crookedness makes our sort travel slower.&lt;br&gt;
There seems to be no way to get ahead.&lt;br&gt;
Likewise I say: drop it!&lt;br&gt;
Like smoke twisting grey&lt;br&gt;
Into ever colder coldness you&amp;rsquo;ll&lt;br&gt;
Blow away.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;The niece:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
+ The old, they say, find little fun in hoping.&lt;br&gt;
+ Time&amp;rsquo;s what they need, and time begins to press.&lt;br&gt;
+ But for the young, they say, the gates are open.&lt;br&gt;
+ They open, so they say, on nothingness.&lt;br&gt;
+ And I too say: drop it!&lt;br&gt;
+ Like smoke twisting grey&lt;br&gt;
+ Into ever colder coldness you&amp;rsquo;ll&lt;br&gt;
+ Blow away.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Poem about Yan'an</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/poem-about-yanan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2022 05:09:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/poem-about-yanan/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Beside the Yellow River, on the bank of the waters of the Yan,&lt;br&gt;
is the yellow earth plateau. &lt;br&gt;
Before the yaodong caves the millstone grinds,&lt;br&gt;
it seems a return to yesterday.&lt;br&gt;
I’m going to Yan’an,&lt;br&gt;
to see the soft passing of time,&lt;br&gt;
to see thousands of hills, everywhere red.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://kobeandpascal.com/images/old-yan-an.jpg" alt="Old Yan&amp;rsquo;an"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://kobeandpascal.com/images/new-yan-an.png" alt="Modern day Yan&amp;rsquo;an"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Worker Reads History by Bertolt Brecht</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/brecht_worker-reads-history/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 10:05:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/brecht/brecht_worker-reads-history/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Who built the seven gates of Thebes?&lt;br&gt;
The books are filled with names of kings.&lt;br&gt;
Was it the kings who hauled the craggy blocks of stone?&lt;br&gt;
And Babylon, so many times destroyed.&lt;br&gt;
Who built the city up each time? In which of Lima&amp;rsquo;s houses,&lt;br&gt;
That city glittering with gold, lived those who built it?&lt;br&gt;
In the evening when the Chinese wall was finished&lt;br&gt;
Where did the masons go? Imperial Rome&lt;br&gt;
Is full of arcs of triumph. Who reared them up? Over whom&lt;br&gt;
Did the Caesars triumph? Byzantium lives in song.&lt;br&gt;
Were all her dwellings palaces? And even in Atlantis of the legend&lt;br&gt;
The night the seas rushed in,&lt;br&gt;
The drowning men still bellowed for their slaves.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title/><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/modernities-morrow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/posts/modernities-morrow/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="modernities-morrow"&gt;Modernities Morrow&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is that trechorous term, whos weight we cannot inherit, whos pressure
sustains and dissolves us at it&amp;rsquo;s beckoning. Perhaps such is the feeling of one
embedded in the fabric of a time unknown to itself, yet so perfectly sure of
it&amp;rsquo;s necessity. How does one speak of a self-reflective epoch, when modernity
wipes all previous memories into a thin glassy veneer? To reflect on our
emergence from the pond water of yesterday&amp;rsquo;s imaginations, my poor poor
uncivilized sisters how hard the brick that cracked the back. In popular
opinion then, modernity is an elevation, an elation from inferiority to
prosperity. Life became easier, cleaner, more controlled, - yet our anxieties
find perhaps no relation in all of history, to speak to who in this lonely
wilderness, why, we are the self assured ones, no? Pride raises us up above
even Newton and his giants. It is difficult to ignore the propulsion which has
taken place, there is no doubt here. Tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s leaps being ever greater, more
prosperous than yesterdays. Can we cope with prospects of decline? Is
modernities energy sapped, as if a simple designation that an event has passed
can circumscribe the cracks left by the ground shaking. The recto to the verso
on the leaf of modernity, the tired, unimaginative, senile declaration of
defeat - what comes after tomorrow, well, the day-after-tomorrow. And so one
wonders whether this is the term slapped on by thinkers exhausted by one of the
central metrics of modernity - volume. Anywhere and everywhere. The struggle to birth the unborn - the morrow which lives in the current moments tensions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://kobeandpascal.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kobeandpascal.com/about/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Literature, science, history, politics and the rest.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>